SYED DANISH HUSSAIN

R-117 Sector 15-A/1 Bufferzone Karachi · 0300-2597869 danish-117@hotmail.com

Looking for an opportunity where I can contribute in the organization success, by utilizing the skills and information acquired through academics and professional experiences. I have Completed my Masters in Public Administration from University of Karachi where my majors was Human Resource Management. I have 8 years of professional HR Experience. I have also completed C.H.R.P. certification from Concord Certification Canada.

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2019 – APRIL 2020 SR. BUSINESS EXECUTIVE, SBT (SMC) PVT LIMITED PAKISTAN

JOB DESCRIPTION

- Employee on-boarding Including Offer, Appointment and Orientation
- Maintaining Master Employee Headcount
- Preparing employee work schedule and updating on the HRMS
- Managing Employee Leave and record keeping
- Payroll Preparation New Hire Details, Promotion, Confirmation, Demotion
- Maintaining and Verification of employee attendance
- Policy Review and development
- Employee Exit interview
- Final Settlement processing
- Employee Engagement activities
- Employee Performance Management
- Conducting employee Disciplinary action session
- Looking after complete life cycle of newly launched BPO International Call Centre
- Providing Orientation and Training when required

FEBRUARY 2013 – AUGUST 2019

HR ANALYST, IBEX JOB DESCRIPTION

- Implementation of HR business processes.
- Maintaining timely and accurate record of payroll related changes (promotions, transfers, separations, provident fund, etc.) of employees on a monthly basis.
- Employee filing and record keeping.
- Handling the queries & concerns raised by employees and business managers with respect to performance, behavior or policy related matters.
- Conducting sessions with employees in line with the disciplinary policy and correction process of the company.

- Issuing of letters with respect to employee's life cycle, including appointment letters, confirmation letters, promotion/transfer letters, visa letters warning letters, show-cause notice, etc.
- Ensure employees' awareness of management's concerns, requirements and complaints and vice versa.
- Work with business managers to ensure consistent HR communications about the Company's practices & policies.
- Work with business managers to build and implement employee retention and motivation tools.
- Timely processing of employee benefits (confirmation of employment, leave management, PF, medical coverage, etc.)
- Maintain reports on employee headcount, demographics, sessions and other reports as defined by management.
- Manage relationship with the Line Managers and handle issues on timely basis across all locations in Karachi.
- Coordinate with Medical Insurance Company regarding employee enrolment and medical claims

FEBRUARY 2012 – JANUARY 2013 HR OFFICER, LIAQUAT NATIONAL HOSPITAL

JOB DESCRIPTION

- Recruitment against vacant positions as per man power plan.
- Hiring process including Offer, Appointment Letter and employee orientation
- Employee Life Cycle (i.e. Resignation processing, End of Probation Processing, Internship Processing, Termination Processing, Annual Increase processing, Promotion processing, Performance Appraisal processing and related HR activities).

OCTOBER 2011 – DECEMBER 2011 OFFICE ASSISTANT, NATIONAL DISASTER MANAGEMENT AUTHORITY

JOB DESCRIPTION

- Maintaining all the records of relief goods received from donor countries, and other donating
- organization
- Maintaining proper schedule of relief goods stocks available in different warehouses.
- Prepare reports regarding relief goods among the head office of NDMA at Islamabad and PDMA
- Karachi.
- Also responsible for proper record keeping of the office record.

EDUCATION

JULY 2011

M.P.A, UNIVERSITY OF KARACHI Majors: Human Resource Management

DECEMEBER 2008

B.COM, UNIVERSITY OF KARACHI Majors: Accounts, Economics and Audit

MAY 2006

F.SC, BOARD OF INTERMEDIATE EDUCATION KARACHI

Majors: Pre Engineering

MARCH 2004

S.S.C, BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION KARACHI

Majors: Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

APRIL 2015

CERTIFIED HUMAN RESOURCE PROFESSIONL (C.H.R.P), CONCORD CERTIFICATION, CANADA

SKILLS

- Employee Relations
- HRMS
- On-boarding
- Grievance Handling
- Automation of HR Process
- Project Management

- Reporting
- Stakeholder Management
- Employee Counselling and Disciplinary Sessions
- Conducting Orientations and training sessions

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father Name : Syed Khalid Hussain
Date of Birth : May 28, 1988
Religion : Islam

Religion : Islam
Nationality : Pakistani
Domicile : Karachi
Place of Birth : Karachi

CNIC Number : 42101-7343794-3